Engr. Syed Faraz Jafri

House No. 1293 Block 2, Azizabad F.B. Area Karachi Pakistan

Mobile Number: +92-300-8923456 E-Mail: engr_sfjafri@hotmail.com



Profile	Key Skills		Present Status		
Being the part of working	Resources Allocation		Assistant Professor in Sir Syed		
organizations, I might be considered	Risk Management		University of Engineering and		
as an energetic and self motivated			Technology - Karachi		
candidate that can provide support in	Engineering Budgetary Estimates		Research Interests		
terms of initiator and leadership	Planning and Scheduling Using P6e		Construction Safety &		
skills. I possess strong numerical,			Management		
analytical and problem solving skills.	Preparing Tenders		Traffic Safety Implications		
In addition to that, a blended research	Client and Staff Liaison		Accident Prevention		
oriented profile is the important part	Site Supervision		Teaching Areas		
of my resume. My ability of quick	Health and Safety Legislation		Construction Engineering/Management		
learning, dedication and willingness	Construction Safety Enforcement		Quantity Surveying and Costing		
of taking responsibilities have always	Data Stage Management and Analysis		Surveying and Levelling – I		
proved me the most profitable asset	MC Feed Constituted decision		Pasia Civil Engineering		
of organization.	MS Excel Spreadsheet designs		Basic Civil Engineering		
Objective			Hydrology and Water Management		
Seeking a career position in a fast pace and	d challenging environment.		Irrigation Engineering		
Academic Background					
M.Sc. (Civil Engineering) University of East London –UEL, London, England (Feb. 2005 to Sep. 2006)					
Course of Studies	Knowledge &	Project Experience			
	Awareness				
Construction and Project Management	BS 5950	Design a spreadshee	t to analyze and design Steel columns		
Construction and Project Management	DS 3930	according to BS-5950.			
Highway and Transportation Engineering	BS 8110	Drainage scheme development.	design of a residential housing		
	ICE Conditions of		of two major new developments on		
Design of Steel & Concrete	Contract	Forecast the impact of two major new developments on the existing road network for the design year.			
	Conduct Traffic				
Earth Quake Engineering & Dynamics	Surveys	Project valuation & cash flow forecast			
BS (Civil Engineering) Sir Syed University of Engineering & Technology, Karachi Pakistan (Jan 1999 to Dec. 200					
Course of Studies			roject Experience		
Construction and Project Management	Environmental	Comparative studies of frame shear wall & tubular			
Construction and Project Management	Engineering	structural system.			
Architecture and Town Planning	Transportation	Use of water reducing admixture & accelerators in			
	Engineering I & II	concrete & studies of their behavior under the impact load			
Engineering Material	Soil Mechanics I & Concreting in Hot & Cold		Cold Weather		
	II Design of				
Reinforced Cement Concrete	Structures	Design of a low cost	housing Scheme		
		A time delay studi	es of an existing road network in		
Strength of Material I & II	Theory of Structure	71 time delay studi	es of all existing foad network in		

Research & Publications

Strength of Material I & II

1. Public Transportation Improvement Validation Model for Metropolitan City Karachi ((Engineering Journal, Volume 18, No. 1, Jan 2014)

Karachi

Theory of Structure

- 2. An Effective and Way Forward approach for Road Safety Acquisition of Knowledge Correlative Study for Pakistan (Engineering Journal, Volume 17, No. 1, Jan 2013)
- 3. Construction Safety culture and promotion, conceptual approach based on the Labor Law of Pakistan (IOSR Journal, International Organization of Scientific Research, June 2012)
- 4. Policy Formulation of Construction Safety associated with Labor Requirements Substantial approach for the metropolitan city Karachi, Pakistan (IOSR Journal, International Organization of Scientific Research, May 2012)
- 5. Safety and Security Policies, Pre and Planned Construction Phase (Key features of quality construction in developing countries, case studies for Pakistan) (Third international conference on construction in developing countries, ICCIDC III, 2012, Bangkok, Thailand)
- 6. Developing Spread Sheet for the design of Steel Column according to BS-5950 (Research Study Master's Program)

Curriculum Vitae Page 1 of 2

Professional Membership

Life member as a professional engineer in Pakistan Engineering Council (PEC).

Chartered Member of CILT (Chartered Institute of Logistics and Transport) Pakistan.

Life Member, Institute of Engineers (IEP) Pakistan.

Life Member, Pakistan Engineering Congress.

Life Member, Aligarh Muslim University Old Boys Association, (AMUOBA) Pakistan.

Work Experience Portfolio					
Organization	Designation	Tenure	Key Responsibilities		
Sir Syed University of Engineering & Technology, Karachi	Assistant Professor	May 2007 to Date	Course Instructor of Construction Engineering, Quantity Surveying & Costing, Hydrology & Water Management. Final year Project Coordinator in Civil Engineering. Final year Project Advisor related to construction management. Factotum in regular examination and supplementary examination.		
Sultan Mehmood Contractors & Engineers (SMC), Karachi	Planning and Site Engineer	January 2007 to January 2008	Planning & scheduling of an expressway project using Primavera P6e Construction procedure in sequence Constrains and their solution. Effective task management. Estimates of bill of quantities & rate analysis. Preparation of bar bending schedules. Health and safety issues. Site inspection and supervision Data collection and analysis.		
Techno Consultant International, Karachi	Civil Engineer	April 2003 to February 2004	Preparation of hydraulic and structural drawings. Provided technical assistance during design, planning and execution process Drafting reports. Data Collection and analysis. CAD drawings. Client and Staff Liaison		

Workshops / Seminars Attended or Organized

Attended a seminar on "Karachi Mass Transit Improvement Plan" as a stakeholder from education department. Organize a seminar on "Construction Engineering" for final year civil engineering students in SSUET, Karachi. Initiate a Construction Safety Awareness Poster Campaign in engineering institutions for safety at work.

Attended a training program based on Environmental Impact Assessment (EIA) holding the PEC credit points.

IT Skills

Primavera 6e competent with management tools and techniques.

Engineering Software: MS Project, SAFE, ETABS, AutoCAD, and STAAD III.

Support: Windows 95/98/2000 Windows 2000 Server, Professional & XP, Installation.

MS Office: Fully competent with all aspects of Microsoft office packages, including Word, Power Point, Outlook, Spread Sheet (Excel).

Achievements & Extra-Circular Activities

Four years consecutive Scholarship holder on merit.

Great interest in reading informative materials, particularly related to concrete technology and construction safety to enhance my knowledge and skills.

References could be furbished on request

Curriculum Vitae Page 2 of 2